# MARCIN DANLOWSKI - Software Developer

marcindanlowski@gmail.com | 791-956-266 | born in March 1995 | Warsaw based



github.com/mdanlowski



linkedin.com/in/mdanlowski



mdanlowski.github.io

#### **ABOUT ME**

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechatronics; joined Accenture in Warsaw as my first professional position to participate in building and maintaining internet banking front-end (earlier core-banking). Currently a happy **Ruby & Vue.js** developer at Roomzilla / Cambridge Innovation Center. Engaged in IT/programming education for children, teenagers and adults. I value curiosity, creativity, rationalism and passion for exploration and improvement.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# RUBY ON RAILS / VUE.JS DEVELOPER | ROOMZILLA / CAMBRIDGE INNOVATION CENTER | APRIL 2019 - NOW

- Using Ruby (2.2 up), Rails (5.2 up), Pry, Devise, Rolify, CanCanCan, RSpec, PaperTrail, Sentry, Rollbar and more.
- Using Microservices / Service Objects with Rails architecture
- Holistically developing functionalities from the back-end (API) to front-end using Vue.js, HAML, Slim, ES6+, CoffeeScript, Webpack, Server-side JS etc.
- Deploying code to production environments, managing Heroku CICD utilities like automatic deploys, error reporting etc.
- Cooperating with client satisfaction specialists and QAs in fixing bugs

#### PROGRAMMING INSTRUCTOR | SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ACADEMY | MARCH 2019 - NOW

- Conducting lectures-workshops on various IT/programming topics:
- Java programming language, algorithmic thinking, algorithm design
- Data structures and their implementations
- The HTTP protocol, networking and workings of the World Wide Web, REST web standard, API development

#### FRONT-END / UX DEVELOPER | ACCENTURE | SEPTEMBER 2018 – MARCH 2019

- Analysis of bugs and errors and application of fixes in the Banking Front-end: HTML (.NET Core), CSS/LESS, JavaScript
- Responsible for assessment and assurance of the website accessibility according to WCAG standards
- Everyday use of **Git and Bitbucket** in code management

## JUNIOR MAINFRAME PROGRAMMER | ACCENTURE | APRIL 2018 – AUGUST 2018

- Worked as a member of a dynamic, multinational Agile team
- Used COBOL and JCL to develop banking applications
- Analyzed and modified existing solutions to accommodate trending needs
- Cooperated with testing team, took active part in Agile Demos and meetings with stakeholders and business partners
- Took active part in knowledge sharing meetings and self-development guilds

# PROGRAMMING INSTRUCTOR (WEEKENDS) | WOWSCHOOL | SEPTEMBER 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2019

- Teaching children and teenagers, introducing them to the programming world, increasing interest and awareness of this field of education the role helped me develop **patience**, **public-speaking skills & dynamic approach to problems**
- Teaching teenagers up to 17yo: HTML5, CSS3 (+Bootstrap), JavaScript (+popular libraries), GitHub
- Teaching the basic principles of programming through fun & adventure children under 13, using environments from MIT and Microsoft, as well as **Python** language
- Building an unconventional and enthusiastic educational environment.

## **EDUCATION**

- BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING | 02.2018 | MILITARY UNIVERISTY OF TECHNOLOGY IN WARSAW MECHATRONICS | Specialization: Industrial Automation and Control Systems, Robotics (GPA 4.36)
- Introduction to Python for Data Science [CERTIFICATE NO. #3,522,257] | AUGUST 2017 | EDX.ORG/DATACAMP.COM
- FULL STACK WEB DEV CERTIFICATE | IN PROGRESS | FREECODECAMP.COM

# **OTHER INTERESTS & HOBBIES**

Interesting people; Neuroscience & AI; Electronics; Cyber Security; Lots of Coffee; The Dakar Rally (will take part one day); Offroad Cycling; Cooking (and eating). Pizza (important to take a lot of to a desert island); Music (guitar, piano). Watching convertibles being launched into orbit (Space exploration and technology); Nature and Biology; Foreign and antique languages; Archeology; Travel and Mountains; Sci-Fi & Fantasy stuff (Dune/Star Wars/Lord of the Rings/Stranger Things)